hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and on this podcast I talk
about how to grow your coaching business
get more clients as well as the mindset
strategies to help you take action and
get results
that's what my business is about is
about you making more money and taking
action I don't just want to fill you up
with knowledge or information so that
you feel smart and you might feel smart
after listening to my podcast but I want
you to also apply it and I want you to
see changes and results
in your life that's why I do this I
don't just do this to Flap my jaws
listen I've done enough of that the last
couple of years if you listen through
the podcast
this is episode number 201 and I'm so
thankful that you're still here that
you're listening that you're plugged in
many of you have become coaching clients
we've got to know each other we've
become friends
and so today
I've just finished a five-day intensive
and I've discovered
a lot about people and I've discovered a
lot about human behavior
I've also discovered a lot about the
marketplace that's out there and I have
a very specific message for people
who
maybe you're not quite ready yet in your
business maybe you have an idea of what
you want to do but you're not quite sure
if you're ready to take the next step
I actually have a lot of empathy
for that because I've been that way in
some areas of my life for years
you know I have certain goals when it
comes to like creating video games and
comic books and telling stories
and sometimes things come come up in my
life
here's what I look at is I think we have
to get honest with ourselves and other
people about
what are our goals for now
and what are our goals for later
and be okay with saying yes this is a
goal that I have but it's not for right
now
at the same time
we have to be real clear on okay
what do I actually want to accomplish
with my life what am I working on what's
my current project
and I think we all should have some kind
of a project on a six-month scope
that we're trying to accomplish
for me my six-month scope is to have 500
members in my group coaching program
we've already had close to
230 people come through the program
which is amazing
and we're close to being halfway to our
goal and that was in about a half a year
so
another maybe 270 members scaling our
ads and adjusting our offer and stuff
like that I can easily get there in six
months so I'm excited about that I have
confidence
knowing that we can hit that goal and
what's fun is once we hit that number
500 members
we will be
a seven figure a year company over a
million dollars per year
right now we're at about a half a
million a year and that's awesome and
it's great and we're thriving and we're
growing and we're impacting people and
it's the best experience of my life it's
the most money I've personally ever made
and we're helping our clients as well
it's not just about me but we're helping
them as well make a ton of money in
their businesses
now here's the deal okay
is
we all put off things
we all procrastinate
we all have reasons why
we don't do stuff and and I want to have
a lot of empathy for this
here's the thing
Mental Health
has been stigmatized
way too much in our culture
I think that it's more of a generational
thing
and
a lot of the people that I talk to and
work with they're over the age of 50.
if you're listening to this you're over
the age of 50 you've probably
maybe thought of when somebody says
mental health or or that they're
struggling with mental health or if if I
told you the reason why you're
struggling is related to your mental
health that you might
think of that as a negative or even a
put down
um I even saw something on social media
the other day
where this lady was like they told you
you should go to therapy because they
wanted to abuse you and I was like wait
a sec what
some people even see the comment of hey
you should probably go to therapy as a
negative insult
and so I think that that's actually
shifting
um I'm a millennial
I am
I will be 30
how old will I be
1988 is when I was born yeah I'll be 35
in March so I'm almost 35 years old
um I feel like 35 is this age where it's
like you know
I have wisdom
about my life but I also know that I
still have a whole lot to learn I'm
young I got a ton of energy still you
know we just had a newborn baby
I have enough energy to be able to work
and to play
and to still
build
the life that I want
um
you know way more than somebody who
might be in their 60s or 70s I have a
lot of clients who are in their 60s and
70s though that I work with
and the reason I'm saying this is this
is I have a lot of empathy for
the fact that
not everybody has
a lot of years left in their life and I
don't want to sound morbid on this but I
talk with my clients I mean I have a
client who's like 80. and yet he talks
in reality he's like you know
I might only have 20 30 years left you
know optimistically right
um my mom
is almost 60.
and yet she has a ton of energy to do
and accomplish a whole lot and she's
doing so much and I'm so excited about
that but it comes from this place of
rest it comes from this place of
self-care
it comes from this place of taking care
of what's going on up here
and so what I found is
in my life when I'm procrastinating on
something when I have a goal when I know
that I want to accomplish something and
I'm putting it off putting it off
putting it off
I'll even notice this with
anybody along the Gambit of the age
range of whether you're you're 20 30 40
50 60 70 or 80.
our belief systems the things we believe
determine our actions okay
so like what we believe
comes out of experiences
this is
basic mindset 101 and if this is your
first time ever hearing this
welcome and I invite you to
really go on a journey of personal
development the more you work on
yourself personally what do we mean by
work on ourselves personally I don't
just mean our physical body
but it really is how we think
how we talk
how we interact
how we interact with the world
how much we love ourselves how much we
respect ourselves
how much grace we give ourselves
that's a huge
part of
personal development is how much grace
do you give yourself when you mess up
when you make a mistake
instead of punishing yourself instead of
beating yourself up you actually
encourage yourself you say hey you know
what
I didn't do my best this time
but I'm going to do better next time
and we grow from every experience
when we have a goal
in our life
and we end up procrastinating on it and
saying okay I'm going to do it next week
I'm going to take care of it next week
I heard this a lot from a number of
people
this past week about my coaching program
we had a ton of people that were like
hey I'd love to join your coaching
program I heard this from like
20 30 people
Jeremiah I want to join your coaching
program but I'm just not ready yet
in my experience
the people who say that
nothing changes in their life
next year
the year after
or the year after that
and
I hope I didn't lose some people by
saying that I know naturally I by me
simply even saying that it offended some
people
that they logged off that they stopped
listening that they tuned me out maybe
they tuned me out when I mentioned
Mental Health
at that point and that's what we got to
get to is we have to break the stigma
of Mental Health
of our life here's what I found
when somebody's like hey I have this
goal
but I'm not ready yet
and they really really have a desire
especially when it's related to
increasing your income because what I
show people how to do is how to make
ten thousand twenty thousand thirty
thousand forty thousand dollars a month
most people
procrastinate
on doing income increasing activities
when they need to work on
their Mental Health
their personal beliefs
their personal development more than
anything else
it's the number one
um area
of their life
they actually don't have to
move things around like they think they
do see because here's what I hear a lot
of people say Jeremiah I'm not ready yet
I'm setting the foundations
I'm
moving some things around I'm making
room in my life to be able to move
forward with this but the truth is like
they don't actually do anything that's
just an excuse that they tell themselves
that's just this thing that they say
that they've been trained to say to
basically
not do anything to basically
procrastinate to put off their goals
and so whenever I end up following up
with those people a year or two or three
down the line they haven't done anything
yet
they haven't moved forward they haven't
moved any of the chess pieces around in
their life they haven't made anything a
priority and they say the same thing
I'm figuring things out Jeremiah I'm
gonna move forward I'm gonna eventually
get started with you I'm gonna
eventually start a business I'm gonna
eventually put an offer out there I'm
gonna eventually coach with you
and
this is why I mentioned the stigma
mental health it has more often to do
with their mental state
their Mental Health
their beliefs about themselves
about what they're capable of
you're more capable
than you imagine that then you can even
think of
to accomplish great things in the next
six to 12 months
I've seen it in my life
I've seen it in
my mom's life I've seen it in my
successful clients lives
and yet I more often than not hear
people
and it makes me sad because
a year to
five years I know somebody who he's been
telling me
for 10 years
Jeremiah I'm getting some stuff in order
I'm gonna get started building my
business once I figure some things out
literally like that script
that people use I'm trying to figure out
my finances I'm trying to think like
what would help them the most again if
that's you
who maybe you you're like he's talking
about me
here's here's the unfortunate part about
this
if you're still listening to this
podcast right now and that has been you
I want to encourage and congratulate you
because you didn't shut down you didn't
stop listening because you felt like you
had to be on the defense
and that's what ends up happening
is most people end up getting on the
defense they end up defending and trying
to prove why they don't need mental
health help
why they don't need to work on their
mindset
why it has nothing to do with their
belief systems why it's a million and
ten other things that are going on
around them why it's other people's
reasons why they can't get started
and they end up just procrastinating for
years and years and years because
they've stigmatized
the very thing
that's gonna actually get them a
breakthrough
and they've stigmatized it for years and
years and years
there's a there's a guy man he has so
much potential
I I'm not gonna name him by name or
anything but I just I
I've been I've been in the coaching
industry for so long I've been around
all the stories all the people
all the excuses all the reasons that
people give why they can't move forward
and then and yet I've seen people with
those same reasons those same excuses
make millions of dollars
and so
what's the difference between those
people it's the people who commit to
their own personal growth their own
personal development
and they destigmatize Mental Health
they destigmatize they stop trying to
defend themselves they stop trying to
prove that they have it all together
they get out of a defensive position and
they get into a
teachable position that says huh maybe
I've been making this excuse
for too long maybe
just maybe
I want to learn what I don't know right
now
I want to learn
what I got blinders on
in my life right now what does Jeremiah
have to say
that maybe I don't know right now
that might help me move the needle
forward
that might help me progress just a
little bit one step further than I am
right now and listen again this podcast
is a great resource for that
I have put this together
I stay faithful to listen I'm committed
201 episodes haven't missed a single
week in 201 weeks come on
you can't tell me I'm not committed to
your success
and I put these out there for free
if you listen through my podcast you
know these aren't a sales pitch they're
not
they're they're me
going in the trenches with you
to help you break past what's limiting
you what's stopping you and what's
holding you back because I know the
potential that people that listen to
this podcast have I know the potential
that humans have to do great things to
do hard things to break past their
limitations and to not let what they're
experiencing stop them from their goals
I've learned so much about myself in the
last couple of weeks
with having a newborn baby as to my
capacity to be more disciplined
to prioritize my time better
to actually take less time to do things
and to make sure to only do what's
important and to set boundaries and to
say no I can't do this
yes I can do this
many times the reasons why
people are stuck
is because they're giving up too much of
themselves to other people
and they're not taking care of
themselves
and they're not making themselves a
priority and and they haven't answered
this one question in years
what do I want
what do I want you know my wife and I
just how to talk
we were feeding our baby
and we just had a talk
right now
about 15 minutes ago
what do we want with our life how do we
want to design our week
how do we want to design
the next month of our life
what do we want to do and what do we
want to choose not to do
in our life
and so we were able to put together a
plan of okay
we're gonna we're gonna take this on
right here
I got some people right here that are
feeling uncomfortable about me
filming so I'm gonna go a different
direction I can usually tell like when
I'm making a podcast that like there's a
whole family and their kids and I can
tell like they they're afraid that I'm
filming them and then I'm gonna put
their kids on the internet and so
I just walk in a different direction if
I feel like somebody is a little nervous
around me filming
that's why I went this way
what ends up happening is we end up
making
other people's
feelings a priority and never answering
this question for ourselves what do I
want
when is the last time that you answer
that for yourself
there's a number of people
who
I meet on a regular basis they don't
know their goals
they haven't sat down they've been in
survival mode for so long if you've been
in survival mode for so long
caring for
other people
making yourself
the last priority in your life
if that's you
if you've been making your yourself the
last priority in your life
and you have
not allowed yourself to express to you
what you want
that's generally tied to
a mental health issue
because you are making other people's
feelings more important than you now
obviously
this was actually a great example of
that like
this this family in my neighborhood they
don't they don't know who I am
they don't know if I'm like doing an
expose on families with their kids or
something like that for 60 minutes you
know and so
I don't want to cause a conflict
bye
making it an issue that isn't there and
plus I end up feeling a little bit
uncomfortable doing that so what I'm
doing is what do I want I want to
operate in my power so I'm going to walk
I'm gonna walk around a different
direction
I'm gonna walk around a different street
because I want to make sure why do I
walk around when I do these podcasts
because it actually helps me think
better
it actually helps me process my ideas
sometimes I get stuck trying to explain
to you guys on the podcast my ideas
and I get stuck sitting in a chair not
moving my body
and so by me going for a walk around my
neighborhood I'm able to actually get my
thoughts flowing I'm able to actually
get my thoughts out I'm able to actually
get these ideas out
something you might be like well
Jeremiah that's distracting
I don't like it when you walk around
I don't like when you do this
and so what I've had to do again for me
is prioritize my time
what do I want
what do I want to accomplish
what life am I creating for myself how
can I show up
for my clients
as the best version of myself and what
that is is it's usually me filming while
I'm walking around in my neighborhood
it's usually me recording
while I'm going for a walk like this
okay
so when's the last time that you've
asked yourself
what do I want
when's the last time that you've
answered that for yourself
what
what do I really want in my life what am
I sacrificing
for other people
and can you start saying no
more often
to what other people demand of you and
start saying yes
more often to yourself
your family
your future or maybe
you have demands from one side of your
family and you're like I gotta say no to
that it's okay
like if you got people in your life
demanding your time
your family your spouse
people at your church
there are some of you you've you felt
like guilty
like I can't say no to certain people in
my life
that
when this person demands of me
that I obey and submit and do whatever
they say and they're the reason why I
can't build my business they're the
reason why
you might need to have a conversation
with that person and say Hey listen this
worked out before that way
now it's not
now it's not working out as much
you know if you're if you have made a
commitment for 10 years to serve at a
church or or at a job and now you're
wanting to build a business you're going
to have to prioritize and move around
your life your decisions when you show
up where you show up how you show up how
people get access to you is going to
change over time
and the reason why we don't do this
is usually related to our Mental Health
foreign
it gets stigmatized
so much
mental health gets stigmatized so often
see we don't realize that me saying no
to Sister Margaret at the church that I
can't show up every Saturday just
because I have for the last 10 years
that's an example right
and that now I'm moving into a new
season and then maybe we end up having
people in our life that guilt us for
expressing what we want and they try to
make us feel guilty
is tied to our Mental Health
that we end up
people pleasing that we end up
sacrificing what we want for other
people
and that we end up
having a hard time starting
to do what we want to do
because we feel obligated to what
everybody else around us tells us that
they need us to do
and so I want you to take a look in your
life
what do you want if you could wave a
magic wand
and nobody would get pissed off here's
the truth people are going to get pissed
off when you start designing your life
how you want people are going to
actually like not like it like they are
going to express disappointment and
possibly resentment and anger towards
you
if you're somebody who is living your
life trying to avoid other people's
anger resentment and disappointment
you are sacrificing yourself
for other people and you are not living
your life based on how you want to
and then you end up excusing it as well
I'm just trying to get some stuff
together I'm trying to figure out my
priorities
when the decisions that you have to make
are actually painful
to move forward are actually
it's gonna hurt like ripping a Band-Aid
off
but you got to do it and you've been
procrastinating it for too long
you know
this is where people get stuck this is
why they procrastinate is we have this
framework we have this system in our
life we have this way that we've lived
our life for so long that to do
something different that to join a
coaching program
that to make time in our schedule to
learn to listen to a podcast to learn
new skills to start to build a funnel in
our business seems impossible because of
all the things that we have going on
all the stuff that we have to do and so
that's why we have to be intentional
instead of letting our life control us
instead of letting how everything has
happened to us to decide for us what we
can do we get to design our life and we
get to say you know what
I don't want to do that on Saturdays
anymore
I'm gonna spend that time learning how
to grow my business
and not feeling guilty not feeling like
you're a bad person for re-prioritizing
and moving things around
now listen I know as I say this there's
going to be some of you I'm going to
lose some people you're going to lose
respect for me just because I said that
please respect for me for saying that
maybe you need to
stop doing some of the things that
you've been doing for so long for other
people
and truthfully the reason why we often
have a struggle doing that
is because
we expect other people to do so much for
us
and we're and we rely so much on other
people that it would pain us if those
people that we relied on told us that
they couldn't help us and so then we
don't say no we don't set boundaries
with others
because we've created this life that is
codependent where we're dependent on the
others and they're dependent on us and
for us to move some things around just
becomes way too difficult mentally to
deal with the conversations the hard
conversations maybe the conflict maybe
the resentment maybe the hatred
and so that's why for you to grow
for you to reach those goals that you
have in your life
you're gonna have to do hard things
you're going to have to make difficult
decisions you're going to have to step
and put yourself into possibly some
difficult and painful situations
and that's why people get stuck in these
patterns for like five to ten years not
doing that
and saying that they can't build a
business
that they can't start learning new
skills it only takes about 90 days to
start creating a coaching business that
makes a hundred thousand dollars a year
and yet people put it off for five to
ten years because they're just
afraid to have those tough conversations
they're just afraid to move some things
around in their life
they're just afraid to confront the real
issue
and they end up living so much in the
comfort zone of what they know
what they're used to and not challenging
how they've always done some things that
they refuse to move some things around
that they refuse to prioritize things a
little bit differently that they refuse
to let people down
you have to start disappointing people
in your life
this year
I've had people argue with me on this
one
because they're like well I don't want
nobody to disappoint me
I expect other people to do day
expectations I expect people to do what
I expect of them
and that standard is what you're also
holding over yourself
that you don't want to disappoint other
people that you always meet everybody's
expectations
you might need to renegotiate
your expectations
you might need to renegotiate what other
people expect of you and I want you to
realize this you get to decide what type
of life you want
you get to decide
what you do for other people
just because somebody tries to convince
you and they might use intimidation
coercion they might even threaten you
and I'm sorry if they do I've had people
threaten me
to fulfill obligations that they feel
that I owed them I have had people
physically threaten me
with violence
to
fulfill what they believed that I was
obligated to do for them
and truthfully when it all came down to
it there was no obligation there now
listen I would say be a person of your
word honor your word if you made a
commitment promise something
do that but sometimes there's necessary
endings sometimes there are times where
we need to Sunset and end certain
relationships certain commitments
to where it doesn't have to go forever
you're not a prison for the next five to
ten years of what everybody else tells
you that you need to do simply because
they benefited for the last five to ten
years because you submitted to their
demands
and that is going to be one of the
biggest breakthroughs
for some of you
that's going to change your life
when you learn
that just because you've always done
something one way doesn't mean that you
have to always do it that way moving
forward
when you learn that you have the power
to create design dictate and decide your
life and that other people don't
actually have that power over you if
they do it's only because you've given
it to them and you can take it back and
it's not a bad thing to take back that
power
you get to decide to create and design
the life you've always dreamed of
and so this is why this one of the
biggest reasons why people
struggle to design their life
is mental health
is because there's beliefs there's
experiences there's pain there's trauma
there's things that we don't want to
repeat there's painful situations that
we don't want to happen again if you got
if you're somebody who got physically
threatened by somebody to fulfill
obligations
you would try to avoid getting
threatened by submitting to everything
people demand of you and that's what I
used to do
I used to
always submit to every demand people
would have of me because
quite frankly I was terrified of being
threatened by people like what I had
experienced
and I had to realize that by healing
I was actually attracting that type of
behavior from people not that I deserved
it
but I was attracting it because I was so
afraid of it that I was actually putting
myself into situations with people that
that type of energy would come at me and
I would end up repeating the same
familiar patterns year after year after
year after year again and again and
again and again over and over and over
again these painful situations
that I didn't want to experience
and it was when I made my mental health
a priority
working with a therapist
you might say I can't afford a therapist
there's a website called sevencups.com
it's free you can talk with people about
your mental health you can talk about
what you're feeling
every feeling
has a belief behind it that comes from
an experience that you had and when you
can identify what that belief is you can
rewire your life you can rewire your
brain even if you're 60 70 80 years old
you can rewire if you're like man I'm
always struggling to do what I say I'm
going to do I've always struggled to
build a coaching business this
might be that unlock for you to start to
do some of those things that you
struggle with for years and it starts by
we have to destigmatize Mental Health
and we have to heal what tried to break
us what tried to stop us
and design your life
I truly believe it
and if you're somebody that wants to
know
how do I make six figures as a coach how
do I make six figures as a course
creator
I'm here to help guide you every step of
the way with this podcast with my events
that I do and with our coaching program
to help you get the results that you
want in your life and your business you
don't have to accept just the default
setting that's been handed to you in
life you can create the life you want
grow your life everybody
and we'll talk soon have a good one
[Applause]